Karl Hubenthal Papers
Karl Hubenthal Papers
- Editorial cartoons, 428 items 14"x 17"
  - Aug-Dec 1963 (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
    Nov. 10 - Waiting--waiting--waiting: civil rights, taxes, Congress, foreign aid
    Nov. 14 - "Gracias, Uncle": oil. Argentina
    Nov. 15 - Flip-flop, Flip-flop: Nikita Khrushchev
    Dec. 6 - 20 year lesson--well learned: Pearl Harbor
    Dec. 16 - Make it a white Christmas: Christmas, charity
    Dec. 18 - Lending a hand: California, natural disasters
    Dec. 29 - Firing-pin ball game: world politics
    1963- "You sure we want to go this route?": unions
    1963 - Tipping the balance: California, New York, population
    1963 - "First y'gotta control the horse!": John F. Kennedy, taxes
    1963 - Join the line-up: sports, Los Angeles
  - Jan-May 1964 (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
    Jan. 6 - The belt tightener: economy
    Jan. 17 - New orbit: John Glenn
    Jan. 23 - Gnats!: Zanzibar, Panama
    Feb. 11 - Swoon music: Congress, taxes
    Mar. 1 - Return the fourth "R"!: prayer, schools
    Mar. 5 - Slow flow: Congress
    Mar. 30 - Puny by comparison: nuclear weapons
    Apr. 2 - The neighbors downstairs are at it again: Brazil
    Apr. 23 - Tourist trap: World's Fair, New York
    Apr. 24 - The ties that bind: unions, Lyndon B. Johnson, elections
    Apr. 29 - Job opportunity: smoking
    May 10 - "James said he was bringing over my present for Mother's Day": Mother's Day
    May 15 -Which way will it fall?: elections, Oregon, Richard Nixon, Barry Goldwater, Henry Cabot Lodge Jr., Nelson Rockefeller
    May 24 - There is a middle ground: Congress, schools, prayer
  - Jun-Aug 1964 (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
    June 12 - It won’t stay buried: Pat Brown, California
    June 18 - Citation for back seat drivers: farm vote, urban vote, Supreme Court, California
    June 25 - Change in climate: Egypt, Scandinavia, Nikita Khrushchev
    July 23 - Wing walker: Barry Goldwater, Republican Party
    July 24 - "I’m cutting you adrift": Charles de Gaulle
    July 27 - Join the line-up: sports, Los Angeles
    July 31 - The final straw: Los Angeles
    Aug. 12 - Tension test: Cyprus, Vietnam War
    Aug. - "You and your paper tigers!": Mao Zedong, Vietnam War
  - Sep-Dec 1964 (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    Sept. 13 - Ain’t love grand?: Republican Party, Democratic Party
    Sept. 14 – Applying the pressure: inflation, automobile industry, Walter Reuther
    Sept. 16 - Buried?: peace
    Sept. 24 - ?-?-?: Vietnam War
    Oct. 1 - Month of the big wind: elections, Lyndon B. Johnson, Barry Goldwater
    Oct. 7 - Tragic backlash: traffic fatalities
    Oct. 30 - Boo!: elections
    Nov. 19 - That's some backlash: weather, California
    Nov. 27 - Helpful sign: Christmas, charity
    Dec. 2 - "Hello, Jolly!": business, Christmas
    Dec. 7 - About time we got fitted: Los Angeles
    1964 - It's all pretty distorted: Republican Party
  - Jan-Jun 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
    Jan. 7 - Here comes the medicine ball again: Medicare, Congress
    Jan. 13 - To the rescue: Ray Bliss, Dean Burch
    Feb. 1 - Fouled: armed forces
    Feb. 5 - Buzzard of '65: Lyndon B. Johnson, Congress
    Feb. 28 - Buck fever: California
    Apr. 9 - What price peace: foreign aid, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Apr. 12 - Sunshine at last': weather, sports
    Apr. 14 - Bean ball: weather
    Apr. 15 - Payton Place: taxes
    Apr. 22 - Swollen sinus headache: weather
    May 20 - Sidetracked again: transportation, Los Angeles
    May 31 - Something for everyone: Lyndon B. Johnson, taxes, labor, business, right to work
    June 10 - There goes the silver lining: money, Lyndon B. Johnson
    June 11 - Magic act: California
    June 16 - Chicken little: stock market, Lyndon B. Johnson, Vietnam War
    June 24 - Not built for a Bikini: Pat Brown, California, budget
  - Jul-Sep 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
    July 1 - Smoggy semantics: pollution
    July 19 - No time to rest an our laurels: space exploration, Russia
    Aug. 5 - Identifiable flying objects: Lyndon B. Johnson, Gerald R. Ford
    Aug. 18 - His favorite trough: crime
    Aug. 27 - Compatible or compatable atmospheres?: space exploration
    Sept. 9 - Sticky problem: peace, U. Thant
    Sept. 23 - Precarious perch: peace, United Nations, India-Pakistan war
    Sept. 24 - Hitch hiker: inflation
    Sept. 26 - Reluctant suicide: California, supreme court
  - Oct-Dec 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
    Oct. 8 - Worry lines: Lyndon B. Johnson
    Oct. 20 - Still our best guide book: National Bible Week
    Oct. 25 - The great escape: Congress, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Oct. 31 - Didn't scare anyone: Fidel Castro
    Nov. 5 - How to get the genie into the bottle?: pollution
    Nov. 8 - "I'd suggest you stop down to f/22": Princess Margaret
    Dec. 1 - That's reaching too far': press, judicial system California
    Dec. 2 - Voice in the wilderness: disarmament
    Dec. 12 - The novelty does wear off: space exploration
    1965 - L.B.J. and me: Pat Brown
    1965 - Cipher crazy: need to remember codes and numbers
    1965 - "I presume you were delayed by the Ecuadorian Navy?"
  - Jan-Feb 1965 (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
    Jan. 2 - Bird watcher: Lyndon B. Johnson, peace
    Jan. 5 - Spring board: inflation, steel industry
    Jan. 6 - Test for a new role: Republican Party, Reagan, California
    Jan. 8 - Capitol dome: Vietnam War, Congress
    Jan. 24 - Less and less cover: draft, college students
    Jan. 28 - Super-hardy perennial: peace, Cold War
    Jan. 31 - It'll never hold: Lyndon B. Johnson, budget, government spending
    Jan. - It's the lower half that counts: nuclear weapons, Alexey Kosygin
    Jan. - Ho Chi Minh trail: Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
    Feb. 2 - Frozen solid: weather
    Feb. 18 - The great race: peace, Vietnam War
    Feb. 27 - Reverting back to the jungle: Africa
    Feb. - Shadow or substance?: economy, stock market
    Feb. - Surprise ! Surprise: California
  - Mar-May 1966 (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
    Mar. 3 - Battered birdie: Vietnam War, Congress
    Mar. 4 - First salvo: War on Poverty
    Mar. 17 - Symptomatic shadow: Watts, civil rights
    Mar. 21 - One dud after another: China, foreign policy, Fidel Castro
    Mar. 28 - Identifiable flying objects: cost of living, elections
    Apr. 1 - Looks lots better wit' arms: sports, Los Angeles
    Apr. 1 - April fool!: taxes
    Apr. 22 - Grows back fast: Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
    Apr. 25 - Due for a ticket: automobile industry
    Apr. 28 - Perilous perch: China
    May 6 - The great D Nide: NATO
    May 9 - Tight green beret: defense, Robert McNamara
    May 16 - Predictable fallout: China, nuclear weapons
    May 20 - Fast running out: Vietnam War, Buddhists, Nguyen Cao Ky
    May 23 - There's a string to it: draft, Robert McNamara
  - Jun-Jul 1966 (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
    June 12 - One-two-punch: weather
    June 17 - It's the new mod look: government spending, debt
    June 22 - Elephant wallow: Republican Party, cost of living
    June 23 - Physical: draft, Congress
    June 24 - It's all done with mirrors: Congress, ethics, Thomas J. Dodd
    July 6 - Hasn't slowed him up much: inflation
    July 12 - Spiked: sports, Czechoslovakia, Russia, Poland
    July 14 - Oh,--oh, 3: Central Intelligence Agency, Congress
    July 15 - Resistance movement: Vietnam War, peace
    July 20 - Oriental torture: armed forces
    July 23 - "Capsule to ground control--where are you?": cost of living
    July 26 - "You're looking under the wrong hood": automobile industry, Congress
    July 28 - Steady diet: Alexey Kosygin, peace
  - Aug-Sep 1966 (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
    Aug. 2 - On the other hand...: traffic fatalities, killings in Chicago and Austin
    Aug. 9 - Make up your mind.: budget, taxes
    Aug. 10 - It's not the "new look": labor, business, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Aug. 11 - Revving up: airline industry, strikes, Congress
    Aug. 16 - Rescue this time?: strikes, Congress, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Aug. 28 - Tabled again: disarmament
    Sept. 7 - Charlie is still on his "trip": Charles de Gaulle
    Sept. 11 - Bucket brigade: inflation, taxes, election
    Sept. 16 - Tether dynamics: Great Society, inflation
    Sept. 21 - Back to work: Vietnam War, United Nations, peace
    Sept. 25 - Bottomless pit: peace
    Sept. 26 - Bug in our ear: sports
    Sept. 29 - Rumor mobile: Lyndon B. Johnson, inflation
  - Oct-Dec 1966 undated (Oversize 4, Folder 8)
    Oct. 2 - Smoke sign: violence, voting, civil rights
    Oct. 7 - Expansion band: Lyndon B. Johnson, government spending, economy
    Oct. 10 - The melancholy days are here again: stock market
    Nov. 3 - Edged in black: forest fires
    Nov. 13 - Food stamp: consumers
    Nov. 14 - We're just out of the foothills: space exploration
    Nov. 17 - Someone else is due for surgery, too: Great Society, Congress
    Nov. 28 - Tall timber: Nelson Rockefeller, Ronald Reagan, George W. Romney, Mark Hatfield, Charles H. Percy, Richard Nixon
    Nov. 30 - Stamp of disapproval: United Nations, China
    Dec. 1 - The suspense is killing us: taxes
    Dec. 9 - Nesting in a loaded gun: Vietnam War
    Dec. 15 - Bugged: espionage
    Dec. 22 - Stuck: budget, defense
    undated - It tastes just as bad: housing, Los Angeles
- Correspondence
  - 1960, 1964 (Box 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
  - 1967, undated (Box 1)
- Writings
  - "Editorial Cartoons: The Role They Play In a Modern Paper" by Hubenthal in California Publisher, Sep 1965 (Box 1)
  - "Reflections of an Editorial Cartoonist" by Hubenthal in The Quill, Jan 1966 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - biographical material, programs, clippings, 1 drawing, 1962; 1965-1967; drawing of Lyndon B. Johnson done while Hubenthal was at the White House (Box 1)